Babaniyi Olaniyi

Well-qualified Data Scientist experienced working with vast data sets to break down information, gather relevant points and solve business problems. I am deeply excited about the time we live in and the rate at which data is being generated and transformed as an asset hence i am keen to leverage my knowledge of data science and machine learning to grasp some of the underlying trends in finance, FMCG, consulting and industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Business Intelligence Data Analyst, May 2020 - Present

Noustique Perfumes S.L / The Alchemist Atelier, Barcelona, Spain

- 1. Leveraged analytics to drive business development, productivity and process improvement and marketing strategies, including customer lifetime modeling, acquisition, retention, win backs and monetization increasing sales by 5% applying machine learning and time series techniques.
- 2. Solving business problems in customer analytics & campaign effectiveness by working closely with marketing teams to develop reports and analysis that are turned into insight and using customer data to gain insights into their behaviour and try to predict their future actions.
- 3. Strong experience tackling real business problems (customer segmentation, churn reduction, sell propensity, adquisition probability, etc.) with machine learning techniques (clustering, regression, classification, etc.).
- 4. Develop and deliver business analytics processes to support effective decision making at senior leadership level.

Finance and Administration Assistant, October 2019 - April 2020

Noustique Perfumes S.L / The Alchemist Atelier, Barcelona, Spain

- 1. Increased productivity by developing automated budget reporting systems and recommending actions by analysing and interpreting data & making comparative analyses resulting in a 25% redundancy reduction.
- 2. Understanding business and its processes through data then applying this understanding and knowledge to help product teams.
- 3. Design & implementation of internal processes (purchases, sales and treasury), management of procurement process (review of invoices, preparation of payments), tax reviews and account record management.

Graduate Research Assistant, July - September 2019

Institute of Economic Analysis (IAE CSIC), Barcelona, Spain

- 1. Created and programmed an end-to-end user-friendly python web scraper using selenium that allows users to seamlessly download data.
- 2. Helped with large survey research projects and provided research support for data processing operations.

PROJECTS/PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Networks in Customer Analysis: Used community detection algorithm on Amazon users to understand the association between customers, reviews and products. Finally, I performed sentiment analysis of customers comments and built a model for classifying the reviews.
- 2. Customer Spend, Satisfaction and Segmentation using Machine Learning Techniques: Clustered customers according to their purchasing behavior and product they bought, then I compared the accuracy of different models (XGBoost, Ensemble methods, etc.) for predicting customer satisfaction and consumer spend (ElasticNet, Ridge, etc.).
- 3. Effects of Macroeconomic Variables on the GDP of Nigeria: I worked on analyzing the economic sectors that contributes the most to GDP and classified these sectors based on their importance using principal component analysis.

EDUCATION

Cipsa Academy, 2019 - Present

Consultant SAP Business One

Autonomous University of Barcelona, 2017-2019

MSc in Quantitative Economics

Kwara State University

Bsc Statistics, 2012 - 2016

CONTACT

E-mail: horlaneyee@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

http://linkedin.com/in/babaniyi

Phone: +34602030649 Address: Barcelona, Spain

SKILLS

- Python, SQL, MySQL, R, Tableau
- Flask, TensorFlow, MS Excel
- Machine Learning, Data Science, Data Analysis, Deep learning, Statistics Adaptability, Decision making, Logical thinking

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- European Union Erasmus Mundus €47000 Award Recipient, 2017.
- Best Graduating Student, School of Statistics & Mathematical Sciences, 2016.
- Clustered customers according to their purchasing behaviour and created a model for predicting customer satisfaction and consumer spend thereby decreasing customer acquisition cost by 10%.
- Helped management understand buyer experience across product search channels. Achieved a 15% improvement in buyer experience rate.

EXTRAS

DataCamp, Data Scientist path

Learned how to: program in popular data science languages, properly manipulate, make predictions using statistics and machine learning and how to utilize collaboration tools like Git and SQL database.

DatasetDaily, Contributor

Perform various statistical & data analysis for a group of over 2000 people worldwide.